大家好，漂亮的人们，欢迎收看这段视频，在这里你们将学习到所需的一切
Hello you beautiful people and welcome to this video where you're going to learn everything you need
了解有关使用命令行移动和重命名文件和目录的所有信息。
to know all about moving and renaming files and directories using the command line.
现在有趣的是，这两个功能都可以用一个命令来完成。
Now the interesting thing is both of these functions can be completed with just one command.
因此，在本视频中，您将了解如何使用envie命令来移动和重命名文件和文件夹。
So in this video you're going to learn how to use the envie command to move and rename files and folders.
通过学习我们将在视频中介绍的一个命令，您将获得两个非常重要的命令
And by learning the one command we're going to cover in this video you're going to gain two very important
使用您的文件系统的能力。
abilities for working with your file system.
谈到效率。
Talk about efficiency.
所以，让我们继续直截了当地谈吧。
So let's go ahead and get right into it.
好的。
OK.
因此，让我们首先讨论一下现在桌面上的重命名文件。
So let's first talk about renaming files now on the desktop.
我有一个文件，名为旧名称Dotti XTi，我想将其重命名为新名称Datti XTi。
I have a file called old name Dotti XTi and I want to rename it to be called new name Datti XTi.
很有想象力。
Very imaginative.
我知道呀。
I know.
现在，要执行此操作，请重命名。
Now to do this do this rename.
使用M.V.命令可以非常简单地做到这一点。
It's really very simple to do using the M.V. command.
所以我们首先来看看桌面。
So first we get to the desktop.
好的，现在我在桌面上，文件实际所在的位置。
OK so now I'm on the desktop where the files actually are.
并将所有名称重命名为新名称。
And to rename all name to the new name.
我所要做的就是羡慕当时的旧名字Datti Xti，这是文件的当前名称，然后
All I have to do is just do envy then old name Datti XTi which is the current name of the file and then
给它起个正午的名字，新名字叫达蒂·西提(Datti Xti)。
give it its nooning which is the new name Datti XTi.
当我按Enter键时，您将看到该文件已被重命名。
And when I press Enter you'll see that the file has been renamed.
好的。
OK.
我们可以使用LS命令看到这一点。
And we can see that using the LS commands.
现在它是一个新名称Dottie XTi Simple，同样适用于目录，所以我有一个文件夹
Well it's now a new name Dottie XTi simple and the same thing works for directories so I have a folder
这里叫旧文件夹。
here called old folder.
正如我们看到的，旧文件夹实际上包含几个文件，所以里面有文件1到10。
And as we can see old folder actually contains a few files so it's got file one to fall 10 inside there.
好的。
OK.
现在重新命名。
Now to rename.
旧文件夹称为新文件夹，并清除屏幕。
Old folder to be called new folder and clear the screen.
您需要做的就是移动旧文件夹，当我按Enter键时，我们可以看到该文件夹已经
All you need to do is move old folder folder and when I press Enter we can see that the folder has been
改名了，就这么简单。
renamed and it's just that simple.
即使我们刚刚更改了文件夹的名称，如果我们打开它，所有文件仍在
And even though we've just changed the name of the folder if we open it up all the files are still in
那里和以前一模一样。
there exactly as they were before.
因此，重命名文件夹不会损坏其中的任何内容。
So renaming folders doesn't damage any of the contents inside.
这样说来，我们如何才能将文件从一个文件夹移动到另一个文件夹。
So with that said how can we move files from one folder into another folder.
这其实也很简单。
This is also actually really simple.
我们所需要做的就是向MOVE命令提供我们想要移动的内容，然后是我们想要的目录
All we need to do is give the move command what we wanted to move and then the directory that we wanted
把他们搬到。
to move them to.
这与copy命令非常相似，您为其提供了一个包含所有内容的列表
So this is very similar to the copy command with the copy command you gave it a list of all the things
您想要复制，然后您给它的最后一个命令行参数是您想要移动的位置
you wanted to copy and then the final command line argument you gave it was where you wanted to move
它必须把它复制到对不起。
it to copy it to sorry.
这与MOVE命令的想法相同。
And it's the same idea with the move command.
好的，如果我们想要将所有内容从新文件夹移到桌面上，那么我们所要做的就是说
OK so if we want to move everything from a new folder onto the desktop then all we have to do is say
从新文件夹移动确定移动新文件夹。
move from new folder OK move new folder.
从这里到这里的所有东西都是桌面。
Everything in there to here which is the desktop.
好的。
OK.
所以医生记忆指的是当前的工作目录。
So the doctor Remember means the current working directory.
这是您可以从shell提示符中看到的，这就是桌面。
And this is you can see from the shell prompt that is the desktop.
我们的意思是将所有内容从新文件夹中移动到当前工作目录，该目录
So what we're saying is move everything from within new folder to the current working directory which
是桌面选项(如果我按Enter键)。
is the desktop option if I press enter.
您将看到所有文件都已移到桌面上，我们可以看到使用。
You'll see that all of the files have been shifted onto onto the desktop which we can see using.
唉，我们得到的是1比10。
Alas we've got a one to 10.
如果我们查看New Folder，我们会发现它们不是刚刚复制的。
And if we look inside New Folder we can see that they haven't just been copied.
它们确实已经被移动了，因为文件夹是完全空的。
They have indeed been moved because the folder is completely empty.
好的，让我们将所有这些文件移回一个新文件夹。
OK so let's move all of these files back into a new folder.
因此，如果我将以文件开头的所有内容移回新文件夹，应该可以处理所有这些问题。
So if I move everything that starts with file back into new folder that should take care of all that.
好了，我们已经将它们全部移回了这个新的文件夹中。
So there we go we've moved them all back into this new folder folder.
好的。
OK.
现在我们怎么才能像旺加一样移动整个新文件夹呢。
Now how can we move the whole of new folder just as Wonga.
例如，我们如何将其移动到我们的Documents文件夹中。
How can we move this into our documents folder for example.
嗯，这也很容易做到。
Well that's really easy to do as well.
而且它的工作方式和你可能预期的一样。
And it works just like you might expect.
我们只需移动新文件夹，当我们想要将其放入Documents文件夹时，我们的目的地在哪里
We just do move new folder and where's our destination when we want it to go into the documents folder
它在我们的主目录中。
which is in our home directory.
所以我们倾斜一下说，我们的主目录是劈开，然后是Documents，所以Documents文件夹在里面
So we put the tilter to say our home directory slash and then documents so the documents folder inside
我们的主目录按Enter键，然后当我们查看主目录并进入文档时
our home directory we press enter and then when we look inside our home directory and go into our documents
文件夹在那里，我们在那里，新的文件夹完好无损地放在那里。
folder there we are there's new folder sitting there all intact.
那么，对于大奖，我如何才能在文档中移动新文件夹，或者将其移动到某个位置并重命名
So now for the jackpot how can I move a new folder inside of documents or move it somewhere and rename
它在同一时间。
it at the same time.
假设我想要将其从Documents文件夹移到桌面，并将其重命名为大奖
So let's say I want to move it from our documents folder to the desktop and rename it to the jackpot
在同一时间。
at the same time.
那我们该怎么做呢。
So how would we do that.
嗯，首先我们需要卖了它，我们卖了它，然后继续我们想要移动的东西。
Well first we need to sell it we sell and move on what we want to move.
因此，假设我们要将新文件夹移动到Documents文件夹中。
So let's say we want to move the new folder folder inside our documents folder.
顺便说一句，这是你应该会觉得舒服的东西，用倾斜符号来代表你的家
And this is something you should be comfortable with by the way using the tilter to represent your home
文件夹，然后是文档，然后是新文件夹。
folder then documents then new folder.
好的。
OK.
最后的劈开是可选的，但我想它是和桌子一起完成的，所以我们会好的，我们会
The slash at the end is optional but I think it comes with the table to completion so we'll well we'll
把它放在那里吧。
leave it there.
好的。
OK.
现在我们要把它搬到哪里去。
Now where do we want to move it to.
我们希望将其移动到桌面，这样就可以说是当前工作目录，因为如您所见
We want to move it to our desktop so we could say the current working directory because as you can see
我们在桌面上。
we're on the desktop.
因此，我们将获得当前的工作目录，但我们将其称为大奖。
So we're going to get the current working directory but we're going to call it jackpot.
所以现在是大奖，因为大奖文件夹不存在。
So jackpot now because the jackpot folder doesn't exist.
新文件夹将成为大奖。
New Folder will become jackpot.
如果我按Enter键，我们将看到已经创建了大奖。
If I press Enter we'll see that jackpot has been created.
里面有来自新文件夹的所有内容或每个单独的文件。
Inside there are all the content or every single one of the files from new folder.
如果我们返回到我们的文档中，我们会看到那个新文件夹已经不在那里了。
And if we go back into our documents we will see that new folder is no longer there.
那么发生了什么。
So what happened.
我们说将新文件夹从Documents文件夹中移出，并将其放入此目录中，该目录
We said move the new folder folder from within our documents folder and put it in this directory which
就是桌面。
is the desktop.
而是一个叫做大奖的文件夹。
But as as a folder called jackpot.
因此，这就是您可以在移动文件夹的同时对其重命名的方式。
So that is how you can move a folder and rename it at the same time.
很棒的东西，对吧。
Pretty awesome stuff right.
现在你就知道了。
So there you have it.
对于您需要执行的任何操作，M.V.命令都是非常简单但非常有效的命令
The M.V. command is a very simple but very effective command for anything that you'll ever need to do
移动或重命名文件。
with moving or renaming files.
在本视频中，您了解了如何使用ENVI命令移动和重命名文件和目录。
And in this video you've seen how to move and rename files and directories using the ENVI command.
这就是它的工作原理。
And this is how it works.
因此，如果您想要移动文件和目录，请先键入M.V.命令，然后再给它命令
So if you want to move files and directories first you type the M.V. command then you give it command
行参数。
line arguments.
您想要移动的所有内容，您可以提供这些内容的倍数，然后是最后的命令行
Everything that you want to move and you can give it multiple of those and then the final command line
参数是要将所有这些内容移动到的目标。
argument is the destination of where you want to move all of those things to.
如果您想要重命名文件和目录，我们一次只能重命名一个文件和目录，但是您可以按照您的要求进行重命名
And if you want to rename files and directories we can only do one at a time but you give it what you
如果要同时移动和重命名，请先重命名，然后再重命名新名称和位置
want to rename and then the new name and location if you want to move and rename at the same time and
您已经在这段视频中看到了如何做到这一点。
you've seen how to do that in this video.
因此，请记住，如果您想要移动或重命名文件，则需要使用NV命令。
So just remember that if you have want to move or rename a file the NV command is what you need.
在上几个视频中，您已经了解了如何修改文件树。
So in the last few videos you've learned how to modify the file tree quite a lot.
现在可以使用Touch和和KTAR命令创建文件和目录。
You can now create files and directories using the touch and and KTAR commands.
您可以使用Ahriman或MDR命令删除文件和目录，也可以复制文件和目录
You can delete files and directories using the Ahriman or MDR commands you can copy files and directories
使用C.P.命令，您甚至可以使用该命令移动和重命名文件和目录。
using the C.P. command and you can even move and rename files and directories using the command.
在下一个视频中，您将学习如何使用命令行实际编辑这些文件。
Well in the next video you're going to learn how to actually edit these files using the command line.
很明显，这将是你们一直在做的事情。
Now obviously this is going to be something that you'll do all the time.
所以，对于所有这些好东西，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for all that good stuff I'll see you in the next video.